Guide to the William Walker Whitehall Johnston Photograph Album of Wales, the West Indies, and the 1st West India Regiment
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
William Walker Whitehall Johnston photograph album of Wales, the West Indies, and the 1st West India Regiment.
1858-1865
GEN MSS 887
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.4
(1 box)
Disbound photograph album with images that document people and the built landscape in the West Indies, circa 1859-1865, and views of people and sites in Wales, 1858. The album includes several studio portraits of Johnston, and a studio portrait that probably depicts his father, Thomas Francis Johnston.
Johnston, William Walker Whitehall, 1835-1886
General note
Title devised by cataloger.
General note
The album lacks boards and pages 1-2.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased by William Reese Co. from Sotheby's (lot 267), November 10, 2009. Purchased from William Reese Co. on the Library Associates Endowment Fund, 2011.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
William Walker Whitehall Johnston (1835-1886)
William Walker Whitehall Johnston was an officer in the British Army. He was born in Trinidad, where his father, Thomas Francis Johnston (circa 1808-1873) served as a Colonial Secretary. In the British Army, Johnston held ranks from ensign to lieutenant-colonel in the 1st West India Regiment. He commanded troops in Jamaica, British Honduras, and West Africa in the Ashanti War, 1873-1874. Johnston married Mary Elizabeth Farrington (circa 1835-circa 1884), circa 1860, and they had two children, Frances Maude Johnston Hilditch (circa 1862-1895) and William Charles Caley Johnston (1870-1918). In 1884, he married Matilda Ricketts (born circa 1856). Johnston died in London in 1886.
Charles Tennant (1796-1873)
Charles Tennant was an English politician and landowner. From 1830 to 1831 Tennant was Member of Parliament for St Albans, and supported the Representation of the People Act 1832 (commonly known as the Reform Act 1832). In 1830 he was one of the founders of the National Colonisation Society, advocating emigration to British colonies. His political publications include The People's Blue Book (1857) and The Bank of England and the Organization of Credit in England (1866). Tennant also owned Cadoxton Lodge Estate in Cadoxton-juxta-Neath, Wales.
West India Regiment
The West India Regiment was an infantry unit of the British Army recruited from and normally stationed in the British colonies of the West Indies between 1795 and 1927. Intially the regiment sought to recruit both free blacks from the West Indian population together with purchased slaves from West Indian plantations. After the abolition of slavery, enlisted men in the regiment were black West Indian volunteers, with white officers and some senior non-commissioned officers from Great Britain.
Scope and Contents
Disbound photograph album with images that document people and the built landscape of the West Indies, circa 1859-1865, and views of people and sites in Wales, 1858. The album includes several portraits of Johnston, and a portrait that probably depicts his father, Thomas Francis Johnston.
Fifty-five photographs chiefly document a stay by Johnston with the Tennant family at Cadoxton Lodge Estate in Cadoxton-juxta-Neath, Wales. Images include portraits, including portraits of Johnston's brothers, as well as several members of the Tennant family, such as Charles Tennant and Henry Tennant; views of the Cadoxton Lodge Estate, including the house and garden; and several views of the Neath Abbey ruins. Other images include views of iron and tin works, Aberdulais Falls, the Tennant Canal, and the beach at the Mumbles near Swansea. Several photographs depict sites in London, including workmen and boys gathered at the construction site of the Victoria Railway Bridge (later known as the Grosvenor Bridge) over the River Thames.
Seventy-nine photographs document sites and people in the West Indies, as well as enlisted men, non-commissioned officers, and officers in the 1st West India Regiment. The photographs of the regiment depict soldiers, officers, military exercises, and barracks. A group portrait shows officers involved in the Morant Bay Rebellion, including Johnston and generals Luke Smythe O'Connor and Alexander Abercromby Nelson.
Photographs of sites in the West Indies include buildings, markets, and streets. Many images depict sites in Nassau on New Providence, including Christ Church Cathedral, Fort Charlotte, Fort Fincastle, Market Street Arch, Old Fort of Nassau, Queen's Staircase, and Vendue House, as well as the residence of the governor and an octoganal-shaped city jail. Images of sites in Kingston, Jamaica, include the Coke Memorial Methodist Church, Kingston Theatre, and Up-Park Camp. Several photographs show the settlement and barracks at Castries, Saint Lucia. Photographs of Port of Spain, Trinidad include views of Marine Square and Almond Walk. Photographs of Havana, Cuba depict the Plaza de Armas, including El Templete, the Palacio de los Capitanes Generales, and a monument to Ferdinand VII of Spain. There are also photographs of the lighthouse at Great Isaac Cay, South Bimini Island. Photographs of sites include several panoramic photographs.
Arrangement
Organized into one series: I. Photograph Album, 1858-1865.
Morant Bay Rebellion -- Pictorial works; Soldiers, Black -- Great Britain -- Pictorial works; Soldiers, Black -- West Indies -- Pictorial works; Aberdulais Falls (Wales) -- Pictorial works; Bimini Islands (Bahamas) -- Pictorial works; Castries (Saint Lucia) -- Pictorial works; Fort Charlotte (Nassau, Bahamas) -- Pictorial works; Fort Fincastle (Bahamas) -- Pictorial works; Havana (Cuba) -- Pictorial works; Kingston (Jamaica) -- Pictorial works; Mumbles (Swansea, Wales) -- Pictorial works; Nassau (Bahamas) -- Pictorial works; Old Fort of Nassau (Bahamas) -- Pictorial works; Plaza de Armas (Havana, Cuba) -- Pictorial works; Port of Spain (Trinidad and Tobago) -- Pictorial works; Tennant Canal (Wales) -- Pictorial works; Victoria Bridge (London, England) -- Pictorial works; West Indies -- Pictorial works; Panoramas; Panoramic photographs; Photograph albums; Photographic prints; Johnston, Francis Hope, d. 1874; Johnston, Walter Mowbray, 1842-1919; Johnston, William Walker Whitehall, 1835-1886; Johnston, Thomas Francis, ca. 1808-1873; Nelson, Alexander Abercromby, Sir, 1816-1893; O'Connor, Luke Smythe, 1806-1873; Tennant family -- Pictorial works; Tennant, Charles, 1796-1873; Tennant, Henry, 1794-1865; Cadoxton Lodge Estate (Wales) -- Pictorial works; Christ Church Cathedral (Nassau, Bahamas) -- Pictorial works; Coke Memorial Methodist Church (Kingston, Jamaica) -- Pictorial works; Great Britain. Army -- Pictorial works; Great Britain. Army. West India Regiment, 1st -- Pictorial works; Kingston Theatre (Kingston, Jamaica) -- Pictorial works; Neath Abbey (Neath, Wales) -- Pictorial works
- Photograph Album, circa 1858-1865; Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged sequentially.
  - Album Page 3. Recto: Portrait of William Walker Whitehall Johnston, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Album Page 4. Recto: Portrait of Henry Tennant (1794-1865), circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Album Page 5. Recto: Group portrait of the Tennant family, including Henry Tennant and probably Charles Tennant, and three women, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Album Page 5. Verso, top: Portrait of William Walker Whitehall Johnston, circa 1859 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Album Page 5. Verso, bottom: Portrait of a man, possibly Thomas Francis Johnston, circa 1859 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Album Page 6. Recto, left: Portrait of William Walker Whitehall Johnston, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Album Page 6. Recto, right: Portrait of a woman, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Album Page 6. Verso, top: Portrait of a woman and three children, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Album Page 6. Verso, bottom: Portrait of two women wearing military jackets and hats, as well as false beards and mustaches., circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Album Page 7. Recto, top left: Portrait of a woman, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Album Page 7. Recto, top right: Portrait of a woman, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Album Page 7. Recto, bottom left: Portrait of a man, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Album Page 7. Recto, bottom right: Portrait of a man, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Album Page 7. Verso, top: Portrait of three children and a ladder, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Album Page 7. Verso, bottom: Portrait of a man with a book, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Album Page 8. Recto, top left: Portrait of a man, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Album Page 8. Recto, top right: Portrait of a man, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Album Page 8. Recto, bottom left: Portrait of a girl and two women, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Album Page 8. Recto, bottom right: Portrait of a woman, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Album Page 9. Recto: Road near a tree with hanging planters and buildings in the distance, probably Wales, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Album Page 10. Recto, top: Cadoxton Lodge Estate, Cadoxton-juxta-Neath, Wales, from a distance, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Album Page 10. Recto, bottom: Woman and man posed standing in the front doorway of the main house at the Cadoxton Lodge Estate, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Album Page 11. Recto: House and garden of Park Lodge, London, England, with a young man seated in the garden and a boy the the doorway, identified as Walter Mowbray Johnston (1842-1919) and Francis Hope Johnston (died 1874), 1858 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Scope and Contents
    Same image appears on Album Page 81, recto.
    Photograph hand-colored.
  - Album Page 12. Recto: Residences at Adelaide Terrace, probably in Great Britain, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Album Page 13. Recto, top: View of a river, probably in Wales, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Album Page 13. Recto, bottom: Man posed standing in front of large house, probably the Dulais Fach House, Wales, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Album Page 13. Verso, top: Portrait of an older boy and young girl; possibly Walter Mowbray Johnston or Francis Hope Johnston with Edith Harriet Elizabeth Johnston (born 1853), circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Verso, bottom: Copy photograph of a portrait of a man in uniform, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Album Page 14. Recto: Portrait of William Walker Whitehall Johnston sitting in a horse drawn cart in the front doorway of the main house at the Cadoxton Lodge Estate, Cadoxton-juxta-Neath, Wales, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Album Page 14. Verso: Portrait of a boy, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Album Page 15. Recto: Yard of Park Lodge in London, with a female servant and a young man and a boy, identified as Walter Mowbray Johnston and Francis Hope Johnston, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Album Page 16. Recto: Aberdulais Iron Works near Aberdulais Falls, Wales, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Album Page 17. Recto: View from the Aberdulais Iron Works toward the Aberdulais Tin Works near Aberdulais Falls, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Album Page 18. Recto: Aberdulais Falls, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Album Page 19. Recto: Aberdulais Falls, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Album Page 20. Recto: Aberdulais Falls, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Album Page 21. Recto: Terrace of the house at the Cadoxton Lodge Estate, Cadoxton-juxta-Neath, Wales, with a man and woman, 1858 September (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Album Page 22. Recto: Arches at the Neath Abbey in Neath, Wales, circa 1858 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Album Page 23. Recto: Sailing ships from the beach at the Mumbles near Swansea, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Album Page 24. Recto: House at the Cadoxton Lodge Estate, Cadoxton-juxta-Neath, Wales, with a woman in the doorway, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Album Page 25. Recto: House and garden at the Cadoxton Lodge Estate, Cadoxton-juxta-Neath, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Album Page 26. Recto: House and garden at the Cadoxton Lodge Estate, Cadoxton-juxta-Neath, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Album Page 27. Recto: Bridge over the Tennant Canal and Neath River, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Album Page 28. Recto: Neath from the house at Cadoxton Lodge Estate, Cadoxton-juxta-Neath, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Same image appears on Album Page 80, recto
  - Album Page 29. Recto: Trees in garden at Cadoxton Lodge Estate, Cadoxton-juxta-Neath, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Album Page 30. Recto: Ruins of Neath Abbey in Neath, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Album Page 31. Recto: Ruins of Neath Abbey in Neath, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Album Page 32. Recto: Ruins of Neath Abbey in Neath, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Album Page 33. Recto: Ruins of Neath Abbey with the Tennant Canal in the foreground in Neath, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Album Page 34. Recto: Man piloting a boat under a drawbridge on the Tennant Canal, with the ruins of Neath Abbey in the background in Neath, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Album Page 35. Recto: Ruins of Neath Abbey in Neath, Wales, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Album Page 35. Verso: Portrait of an enlisted man in the 1st West India Regiment, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Album Page 36. Recto: Copy photograph of a painting of two women in profile, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Album Page 36. Verso, top: Market Street Arch, Nassau, New Providence; image includes a black man in uniform, probably an enlisted man in the 1st West India Regiment, as well as a woman under the arch, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Album Page 36. Verso, bottom: Harbor and houses at Nassau, New Providence, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Album Page 37. Recto: Copy photograph of a painting of two women in profile, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Album Page 38. Recto: Barracks for the 1st West India Regiment at Old Nassau Fort in Nassau, New Providence; image includes enlisted men in the 1st West India Regiment, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Album Page 38. Verso: Street in Nassau, New Providence; image includes six black men in uniform, probably enlisted men in the 1st West India Regiment, as well as three white men, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Album Page 39. Recto, top: Residence of the Governor in Nassau, New Providence; includes an enlisted man in the 1st West India Regiment, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Album Page 39. Recto, bottom: Residence of the Governor in Nassau, New Providence, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Album Page 39. Verso, top: Portrait of a man, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Album Page 39. Verso, top: Portrait of a woman, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Same image as Album Page 70, recto
  - Album Page 40. Recto, top: Group of enlisted men in the 1st West India Regiment in camp, with Fort Charlotte in the background, in Nassau, New Providence, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Album Page 40. Recto, bottom: Group of enlisted men and officers in the 1st West India Regiment in camp, as well as a black woman, with Fort Charlotte in the background, in Nassau, New Providence, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Album Page 41. Recto: Large group of workmen and boys gathered at the construction site of the Victoria Railway Bridge (later known as the Grosvenor Bridge) over the River Thames in London, England, 1859 May (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Album Page 42. Recto: Barracks for the 1st West India Regiment at Old Nassau Fort in Nassau, New Providence, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    This photograph forms a panorama of the site when combined with the photograph on Album Page 44 in Box 1, folder 42
  - Album Page 43. Recto: Buildings in Nassau, New Providence, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Album Page 44. Recto: Barracks for the 1st West India Regiment at Old Nassau Fort in Nassau, New Providence, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    This photograph forms a panorama of the site when combined with the photograph on Album Page 42 in Box 1, folder 40
  - Album Page 45. Recto: Group of enlisted men and officers in the 1st West India Regiment in camp, as well as a black woman, with Fort Charlotte in the background, in Nassau, New Providence; the enlisted men are posed in formation with an officer reviewing them, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Album Page 46. Recto, top: Residence of the Governor in Nassau, New Providence; includes an enlisted man in the 1st West India Regiment, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Album Page 46. Recto, bottom: Residence of the Governor in Nassau, New Providence, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Album Page 47. Recto: Buildings in Nassau, New Providence, includes the octoganal-shaped city jail (later the Nassau Public Library), circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Album Page 48. Recto: Parliament Street and buildings in Nassau, New Providence, includes the octoganal-shaped city jail (later the Nassau Public Library), circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Album Page 49. Recto: Street scene, probably a stone quarry operation, in Nassau, New Providence, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Album Page 50. Recto: Parliament Square from Prince George Wharf in Nassau, New Providence, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Album Page 51. Recto: Group of enlisted men and officers in the 1st West India Regiment with field artillery in Nassau, New Providence, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Album Page 52. Recto: George Street and buildings in Nassau, New Providence, includes Vendue House and Christ Church Cathedral, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Album Page 53. Recto: Street and buildings in Nassau, New Providence, includes a strorefront for R. Sweeting, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Album Page 54. Recto: People, including a black soldier in uniform, black women, and white men, in front of the barracks for the 1st West India Regiment at Old Nassau Fort in Nassau, New Providence; the tower for Christ Church Cathedral is visible on the right side of the image, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Album Page 55. Recto: People, including a black soldier in uniform and five white men, in the ordinance yard in front of the barracks for the 1st West India Regiment at Old Nassau Fort in Nassau, New Providence; other soldiers are visible on the verandas of the barrackes, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Album Page 56. Recto: Bay Street and buildings in Nassau, New Providence; market stalls visible on the left of the image, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Album Page 57. Recto: Bay Street and buildings in Nassau, New Providence; market stalls visible on the right of the image, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Album Page 58. Recto: Street in Nassau, New Providence; image includes three black men in uniform, probably enlisted men in the 1st West India Regiment, as well as six white men, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Album Page 58. Verso: Great Isaac Cay Lighthouse, South Bimini Island, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Album Page 59. Recto: Great Isaac Cay Lighthouse, South Bimini Island, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Album Page 59. Verso: Fort Fincastle in Nassau, New Providence, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Album Page 60. Recto: Queen's Staircase, a hand-hewn stairway in a limestone wall, in Nassau, New Providence, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Album Page 60. Verso: Bird's eye view of Castries, Saint Lucia, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Album Page 61. Recto: Barracks at Castries, Saint Lucia, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Album Page 61. Recto: Veranda of barracks at Castries, Saint Lucia; image includes soldiers in uniform and a woman, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Album Page 62. Recto: Veranda of barracks at Castries, Saint Lucia; image includes a black woman in the foreground, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Album Page 62. Verso: Group portrait of black children and women among thatched houses on Saint Lucia, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Album Page 63. Recto: Building and boats at Castries, Saint Lucia, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Album Page 63. Verso: Bird's eye view of Castries, Saint Lucia, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Album Page 64. Recto: Bird's eye view of Castries, Saint Lucia, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Album Page 64. Verso: Group of enlisted men from the 1st West India Regiment in the midst of bayonet exercises and reviewed by officers and non-commissioned officers at Fort Charlotte in Nassau, New Providence, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Album Page 65. Recto: Group of enlisted men from the 1st West India Regiment at ease at Saint Lucia, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Album Page 65. Verso: Group of seven officers from the 1st West India Regiment posed standing on the steps of the barracks at Castries, Saint Lucia; William Walker Whitehall Johnston is third from the left, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Album Page 66. Recto: Group of six officers from the 1st West India Regiment posed standing on the steps of the barracks at Nassau, New Providence; William Walker Whitehall Johnston is third from the left and holds a glass negative holder, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Album Page 66. Verso: Black man posed standing with two pack mules, with an enlisted man from the 1st West India Regiment in the background, probably at Saint Lucia, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Album Page 67. Recto: Group of eight white men, two of the men reclining on the ground, probably at Saint Lucia, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Album Page 67. Verso: Overview of a hilly country with houses, pastures, and trees, probably at Saint Lucia, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Album Page 68. Recto: Three photographic prints mounted one above another that form a panoramic view of Castries, Saint Lucia, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Album Page 69. Recto: Group of fourteen non-commissioned officers from the 1st West India Regiment, probably in front of the barracks at St. Lucia near a door marked for the office of the quartermaster, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Album Page 70. Recto: Studio portrait of a woman, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    Same image as Album Page 39, verso, top
  - Album Page 71. Recto: Group studio portrait of officers involved in the Morant Bay Rebellion; Officers identified, left to right, Ensign R. F. Ballantine, Captain O'Connor, Captian William Walker Whitehall Johnston, Brigadier General Luke Smythe O'Connor, Lieutenant Adcock, Brigadier General Alexander Abercromby Nelson, and Ensign Lanyon., 1865 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    Photographic detached from page with manuscript identifications on its verso
  - Album Page 71. Verso, top: Left-side photographic print that forms a panoramic view of Kingston, Jamaica; this image includes the barracks, circa 1865 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    Forms a panoramic image with prints on Album Page 72, recto, top, and Album Page 71, verso, bottom
  - Album Page 71. Verso, bottom: Right-side photographic print that forms a panoramic view of Kingston, Jamaica; this image includes the Coke Memorial Methodist Church, circa 1865 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    Forms a panoramic image with prints on Album Page 71, verso, top, and Album Page 72, recto, top
  - Album Page 72. Recto, top: Center photographic print that forms a panoramic view of Kingston, Jamaica; this image includes the Kingston Theatre, circa 1865 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    Forms a panoramic image with prints on Album Page 71, verso, top and bottom
  - Album Page 72. Recto, bottom: Buildings in Kingston, Jamaica, circa 1865 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Album Page 72. Verso: Tree at crossroads near Morant Bay, Jamaica; rebels during the Morant Bay Rebellion assembled by this tree on October 12, 1865, immediately before attacking the Court House, circa 1865 (Box 1, Folder 70)